Seattle, WA | siqizhang1130@gmail.com | 206-739-4709 | https://github.com/siqizhang1130

# DATA ANALYST

Technical-driven analyst with two-years of experience in successfully delivering enterprise-level solutions in marketing, sales, and products. Collaborate with all levels of an organization to define and understand business problems and deliver lasting value in a process and technical solution that is stable, scalable, and directly influences efficiency, customer experience, and profits. Two years of academic experiences applying statistical, econometric, and machine learning models for solutions in analysis and prediction issues.

#### KEY STRENGTHS

SQL | R | Python | Tableau | Power BI | ETL | Data Visualization | Interactive Dashboard | Shiny | AWS (EC2, S3, RDS, Redshift)
Data Modeling | Machine Learning (KNN, Logistic Regression, Neuron Network) | Statistical Analysis | Time Series Models
Forecasting | A/B Testing | Large-scale Complex Datasets | Google Analytics | MS Excel

### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Business Analytics and Finance Dual Degree, Seattle University, Seattle, WA, 09/2018 – Present GPA: 3.93/4.0 (Dean's Honor List)

Bachelor of Art, Business English (Intl. Finance), Guangdong University of Foreign Studies, Guangzhou, China, 2016

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Seattle University | Seattle, WA | 03/2019 - Present

### Data Analyst, Computer Lab of Albers School of Business and Economics

- Extracted data from computer lab database and visualized in Tableau to identify laptop demand by different categories, implemented linear programming in R to coordinate laptop delivery schedules.
- Predicted future demand using time series and logistic regression models with Python, and provided computer maintenance frequency advice to supervisor, reduced workload of computer maintenance by 30%.

#### Lutello | Seattle, WA | 03/2020 - 05/2020

## **Marketing Analyst Intern**

- Implemented Google Analytics to analyze website performance, and identified ways to improve their search engine optimization, increased website traffic by 40% and reduced bounce rate by 20%.
- Worked directly with CEO and created competitive comparison analysis of company's SEO performance, content marketing etc. to improve web and social media presence.
- Created an in-depth 30 page website and social media analysis report to help the company optimize its marketing activities and customer awareness.

#### HSBC | Shenzhen, China | 06/2016 – 07/2018

## Financial Analyst, Retail Banking & Wealth Management Department

- Queried and manipulated data from various systems, visualized cashflow trends with Power BI, identified root causes and reported findings to the Branch Manager to support the monthly operation strategy.
- Leveraged DAX to set up the financial models in Power BI, calculated insurance premium across different customer groups.
- Proposed to extract investment behavior data for 30+ high net-worth clients, and applied logistic regression and decision tree model with Python Sklearn to explore potential investment needs; brought in over \$5M new investment funds to the branch.
- Analyzed and forecasted currencies and precious metals markets with technical and economic indicators in Bloomberg Terminal.

#### DATA ANALYSIS PROJECTS

Florist Database Design (SQL, Tableau) – Built an ER model, generated physical database system, stored database in AWS RDS, and created SQL queries and Tableau visuals to analyze sales revenue and manage online orders, customer information, and inventory.

**Seattle Airbnb Host Marketing Strategies (R, Shiny)** – Visualized Seattle Airbnb listings data using ggplot, and created Shiny dashboard and storyboard for analysis and presentation. Implemented multiple linear regression model and t-test to define significant variables that affected the revenue of Seattle Airbnb hosts.

**PACCAR Parts Lead Time Forecasting (Python)** – Utilized knowledge of Supply Chain, built Machine Learning models and time-series models in Python to predict Safety Stock Quantity for the materials department in order to optimize inventory of PACCAR Parts.

**Hotel Demand Forecasting (Python)** – Implemented advanced booking models, time-series models, Machine Learning models and combined models to forecast hotel demand for next six months. The final model minimized MASE to 77% and reduced errors by 23%.